A Guide to the Executive Papers of Governor John Floyd, 1830-1834
Library of Virginia
- Executive Papers of Governor John Floyd, 1830-1834., Extent: 14 boxes. (Box 1-14)
  Additional significant correspondence includes the following: John Tyler to James M. Selden re. his estate in New Kent County called Woodsey's (1830 Sept. 16); Gustavus A. Myers, Chairman of the Committee of the Common Council, encl. a resolution re. conveying the waste water from the pump in the enclosure around the Governor's house to the gutter on 13th Street (1830 Nov. 29); Robert Triplett re. unsatisfied claims of the officers, soldiers, & seamen of the Virginia State Line during the Revolution to military bounty land in Kentucky (1830 Dec. 28); David E. Moore re. proposals for supplying the guard at the Lexington Arsenal (1830 Dec. 23); John H. Peyton, President of the Court of Directors of the Western Lunatic Hospital, encl. a report and list of patients (1831 Jan. 8); John Coulter resigning as judge of the Court of Appeals (1831 Mar. 23); Robert B. Taylor resigning as major general and encl. a letter accepting an appointment as judge of the General Court (1831 Apr. 25); John Y. Mason resigning his seat in the Virginia Senate (1831 Apr. 22); William Daniel accepting his commission as judge of the General Court and of the Superior Courts of Law & Chancery (1831 May 3); James Monroe resigning as a visitor of the University of Virginia due to poor health (1831 May 14); Thomas W. Gilmer accepting his appointment as agent under the act of the General Assembly concerning certain claims of the state of Virginia against the U.S. (1831 June 28); Dabney Carr accepting an appointment as visitor of the University of Virginia (1831 June 15); Dabney Carr resigning as visitor of the University of Virginia (1831 July 1); William DuVal re. claims of Virginia against the U.S. during the Revolutionary War (1830 Nov. 1 & 15, & 1831 Mar. 19); various county clerks re. the furnishing of seals of the Superior Court of Law for the county (1831 July); William Broadnax accepting his appointment as visitor of the University of Virginia (1831 Aug. 17); William Cave, Indiana, re. the whereabouts of Boxley, a fugitive from justice (1831 Sept. 5); Benjamin F. Brown proposing to rent the Boring Mill (1831 Oct. 1); R. M. Patterson, Chairman of the Faculty of the University of Virginia, re. a volunteer association for the purpose of receiving military tactics (1831 Oct. 24); R. M. Patterson re. arms for the use of the students of the University of Virginia (1831 Nov. 3); Anonymous re. the dangers of the assembly of negroes at the market in Richmond (undated); Clement White, Superintendent of Quarantine at the Port of Richmond, re. the quarantine of vessels (1831 Dec. 19 & 28; 1832 Jan. 8, 16, & 27, Feb. 12 & 29, Apr. 25, July 16 & 23, Sept. 18; 1834 Jan. 14, 17, & 27); John H. Peyton encl. the annual report of the Western Lunatic Asylum (report not included) (1832 Jan. 7); A. P. Hill recommending Map Green as colonel of cavalry for Culpeper County (1832 Jan. 16); John M. Patton re. proceedings of a convention of free negroes of the United States at Philadelphia from 6 to 11 June 1831 (1832 Jan. 21); letters of application for vaccine agent (1832 Feb. 15); John A. Washington, Mt. Vernon, re. the resolutions of the General Assembly for the removal of the remains of General Washington (incl. letter of John Marshall declining to cooperate) (1832 Mar. 5); William H. Richardson re. papers & books in the roof of the Capitol, their removal, & the employment of someone to examine & arrange them (1832 May 8); S. M. Stillwell encl. a copy of a report to inquire into the expediency of a total abolition of capital punishment (1832 June 3); Henry Gibson requesting an order for salutes to be fired on the anniversary of the American Independence (1832 June 19); Thomas W. Gilmer re. receipt & transmission to the Treasury of Virginia the money which will be paid from the U.S. for adjusting the claims of Virginia against the General Government (1832 June 26); Conway Whittle, Collector's Office, re. the act of the General Assembly to cede to the U.S. a certain piece or parcel of land on Assateague Island in the county of Accomack for the purpose of erecting a lighthouse (1832 June 27); James Cabaniss re. the propriety of disposing of the remains of the Old Capitol including the walls, stone steps, & stone floor (1832 Sept. 20); James Semple accepting an appointment as judge of the General Court & Superior Court of Law & Chancery for the 4th Judicial Circuit (1832 Sept. 11); William Brockenbrough re. the resignation of William Browne as judge of the General Court (1832 Aug. 27); A. P. Upshur re. a demand from the Executive of New York for the surrender of slaves who stole a large boat from Peter Bowdain and absconded to New York (1832 Oct. 4); Charles James Faulkner re. his commission for the settlement of the western boundary of Maryland (1832 Nov. 6); George Tucker, Chairman of the faculty of the University of Virginia, encl. a resolution of the faculty requesting an annual grant for the use of the Library (1832 Nov. 19); James Cabaniss encl. a valuation of the remains of the former Capitol in Williamsburg (1832 Nov. 26); Richard Coke, Jr., re. commissioners appointed by the states Delaware & Maryland to superintend a survey of the sounds on the Atlantic Coast between Capes Charles & Henlopen (1833 Dec. 14); Thomas B. Randolph resigning as brigadier general of the 4th Brigade to become sergeant at arms to the House of Representatives (1833 Jan. 1); R. A. McPherson, Indianapolis, re. the presence of George Boxley who was the leader of an insurrection in Spotsylvania County(1833 Feb. 7); B. W. Leigh, Charleston, re. the States Rights Party & the preservation of the Union as Commissioner of Virginia to South Carolina (1833 Feb. 22); B. W. Leigh, Columbia, re. the Convention of South Carolina on the recent act of Congress modifying the tariff, the mediation of Virginia, & the coercion law (1833 Mar. 13); John S. Gallagher re. his appointment as one of the commissioners to settle the western limits of the state and the boundary line between Virginia & Maryland (1833 May 9); John McGee, Indianapolis, requesting an appointment as an agent to Virginia to apprehend George Boxley (1833 May 9); J. M. Mason accepting a commission as a visitor of the University of Virginia (1833 July 1); G. Millan re. a suspicious charlatan who is endeavoring to cause the slaves in Fairfax to make insurrection (1833 Sept. 9); J. L. Edwards, War Dept. Pension Office, re. claims founded on service in the Public Armory at Fredericksburg during the Revolutionary War (1833 Sept. 10); Peter A. Browne, Philadelphia, re. the expediency of a topographical, geological, mineralogical, & oryctological survey of Virginia (1833 Sept. 30); James Barron, U.S. Navy Yard, Philadelphia, re. his service during the Revolutionary War (1833 Sept. 30); Committee of students at the University of Virginia requesting sixty new muskets, cartouche boxes, & belts (1833 Oct. 7); Thomas P. Culbreth, Clerk of the Executive Council of Maryland, re. engineers for the survey of the coast & sounds between Cape Charles & Lewistown (1833 Oct. 30); Robert C. Nicholas, U.S. Attorney General, encl. a letter from Levi Woodbury, Navy Dept., re. the ceding of jurisdiction from the governor to the U.S. over certain lands near Norfolk (1834 Feb. 12); Robert C. Nicholas resigning as Director of the Penitentiary (1834 Jan. 9), and David E. Moore, Captain of the Lexington Arsenal, re. defects in the laws for the government of the Arsenal (1834 Feb. 24).
  Other noteworthy items include: proclamations by the governor & lieutenant governor offering rewards for the apprehension of escaped convicts (1830 Apr. 10, May 8, June 24, Nov. 20, Dec. 27; 1831 Mar. 22, Oct. 27; 1832 Mar. 2, May 28, Sept. 28, Nov. 13 & 23, Dec. 10; 1833 Apr. 16, June 11, July 9, Aug. 23, Sept. 23, Dec. 11; 1834 Jan. 20, & Feb. 14); proclamation that a majority of qualified voters is in favor of the ratification of the Constitution (1830 July 1); proclamation for an election to fill the vacancy caused by the resignation of Philip P. Barbour from the House of Representatives (1830 Oct. 23); memorial of the American Convention for promoting the abolition of slavery and improving the condition of the African race (1831 Jan. 10); certificate of qualification of John Floyd as governor (1831 Mar. 31); certificates of qualification of Peter V. Daniel, Daniel A. Wilson, & Wyndham Robertson as members of the Privy Council (1831 Mar. 31); proclamation that elections for Congress not be held in the month of April for the present year (1831 Mar. 8); proclamation re. an election to fill the vacancy caused by the resignation of John Y. Mason in the Virginia Senate (1831 May 25); proclamation for an election to supply the vacancy in the Virginia Senate by the resignation of Joseph W. Chinn (1831 June 11); advice of the Council re. the death of James Monroe (1831 July 8); certificate of oath of Lawson Burfoot as treasurer (1832 Feb. 1); proclamation for an election to supply the vacancy in the Virginia Senate occasioned by the resignation of William Armistead (1832 Mar. 22); proclamation for an election to supply the vacancy in the Virginia Senate occasioned by the resignation of Charles S. Morgan (1832 Mar. 26); proclamation that the Circuit Superior Court of Law & Chancery in Williamsburg be held at the courthouse of James City County on account of the fire in Williamsburg (1832 Apr. 11); bond of William S. Scott as vaccine agent (1832 Apr. 19); circular of a proceeding of a meeting of the Pennsylvania Society for the promotion of manufacturers & the mechanic arts (1832 May 17); act for the apportionment of representatives among the several states according to the Fifth Census (1832 May 22); proclamation of Lt. Gov. Wyndham Robertson requesting the sheriffs of the several counties to delay bringing any convicts to the Penitentiary on account of a cholera outbreak (1832 Sept. 28); list of persons who have qualified as citizens of Virginia between 1 October 1831 & 1 October 1832 in Henrico County (1832 Oct. 1); list of aliens who have taken the oath of naturalization for the year ending 1 October 1832 in Logan County (1832 Oct. 1); proclamation of Lt. Gov. Wyndham Robertson for an election to supply the vacancy in the House of Representatives caused by the death of Charles C. Johnston (1832 Oct. 2); proceedings of the Board of Directors of the Penitentiary containing resolutions to employ an additional assistant keeper & nurses (includes cholera reports & correspondence) (1832 Oct. 12); proclamation for the election of electors for each county to choose a president & vice president of the U.S. (1832 Nov. 21); proclamation requiring the sheriff of Norfolk County, etc., to cause an election to be held for a suitable person to replace William C. Holt in the Virginia Senate (1832 Dec. 1); proclamation for an election to replace Philip Doddridge as a member of the House of Representatives (1832 Dec. 10); resolution of New Hampshire approving of the proclamation of the President on 10 December 1832 regarding his exercise of veto (1833 Jan. 1); resolution of the Court of Directors for the Lunatic Hospital in Williamsburg that William W. Vest be commissioned as director in the room of James Semple, Jr. (1833 Jan. 7); order of Governor Floyd for improvements to the Penitentiary (includes correspondence from C. S. Morgan, Lewis W. Chamberlayne, & Lewis G. Sewell) (1833 Apr. 9); proclamation for an election to supply the vacancy in the Virginia Senate occasioned by the resignation of William McComas (1833 May 20); proclamation of Lt. Gov. Robertson directing the sheriffs of the counties in the 5th Congressional District to cause an election to be held to fill the vacancy occasioned by the death of John Randolph (1833 June 22); proceedings of the Board of Directors of the Penitentiary (1833 Aug. 26); proclamation for an election to supply the vacancy in the House of Delegates for Louisa County occasioned by the death of Charles Dabney (1833 Sept. 25); proceedings of the Court of Directors of the Western State Lunatic Hospital recommending the appointment of Edward Valentine (1833 Nov. 2) & Thomas J. Michie (1833 Nov. 14); proceedings of the Directors of the Lunatic Hospital in Williamsburg recommending Thomas O. Cogbill as director to fill the vacancy left by the death of George Morrison (1834 Feb. 7); proclamation for an election to supply the vacancy in the House of Representatives occasioned by the death of Thomas T. Bouldin (1834 Feb. 20); and the certificate of qualification of Littleton W. Tazewell as governor of Virginia (1834 Mar. 31).
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - 1830
    - March
      - 4-16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 17-31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - April
      - 2-19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 20-30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - May
      - 1-18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 19-29 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - June
      - 1-19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 20-30 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - July
      - 1-13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - 14-30 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - August (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - September (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - October
      - 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 17-30 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - November
      - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 11-24 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 25-30 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - December (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Pardons (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1831
    - January
      - 3-21 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - 22-31 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - February (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - March
      - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 16-31 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - April
      - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - 16-30 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - May
      - 1-17 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - 18-30 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - June
      - 1-13 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - 14-20 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - 21-30 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - July
      - 1-4 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - 5-10 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - 11-14 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 15-30 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - August
      - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 11-20 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 22-30 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - September
      - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - 11-19 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - 20-25 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - 26-30 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - October
      - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - 11-22 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - 23-31 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - November
      - 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - 11-22 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - 23-30 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - December
      - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - 16-31 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Pardons
      - October (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - November (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - December (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1832
    - January
      - 2-8 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - 9-21 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - 22-31 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - February
      - 1-12 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - 13-17 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - 20-29 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - March
      - 1-10 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - 12-20 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - 21-30 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - April
      - 1-15 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - 16-31 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - May
      - 1-10 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 11-20 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - 21-30 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - June
      - 1-11 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - 12-21 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - 22-30 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - July
      - 2-10 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - 12-20 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - 21-31 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - August
      - 2-10 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - 11-20 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - 21-31 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - September
      - 1-10 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - 11-20 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - 21-30 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - October
      - 1-10 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - 11-20 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - 21-31 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - November
      - 1-9 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - 10-19 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - 20-30 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - December
      - 1-8 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - 10-19 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - 22-31 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1833
    - January
      - 1-11 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - 12-31 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - February
      - 1-14 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - 16-28 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - March
      - 1-9 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - 11-20 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - 21-31 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - April
      - 1-15 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - 16-30 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - May
      - 1-10 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - 13-20 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - 22-31 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - June
      - 1-10 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - 11-15 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 17-24 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 25-29 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - July
      - 1-11 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - 12-19 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - 22-31 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - August
      - 1-15 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - 16-23 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - 25-31 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - September
      - 1-10 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - 11-30 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - October
      - 1-15 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - 19-31 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - November
      - 1-10 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - 11-18 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - 19-24 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - 25-28 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - 29-30 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - December
      - 1-10 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - 11-31 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 1834
    - January
      - 1-10 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - 11-20 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - 22-31 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - February
      - 3-15 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - 16-25 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - 26-28 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - March
      - 1-14 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - 16-31 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Oversized (Clamshell Box)
  - 1830
    - May 22 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - June 19 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - July 1 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - July 2 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - July 21 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Oct. 9 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Nov. 20 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Dec. 10 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1831
    - Feb. 4 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Mar. 18 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Mar. 22 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - June 29 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - July [N.D.] (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Aug. [N.D.] (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Sept. 19 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Nov. 28 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Pardons - October
      - Amos (slave) (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Jarrell, Simon (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - 1832
    - Feb. 15 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Nov. [N.D.] (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Dec. 26 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - 1833
    - Jan. 16 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Mar. 1 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Mar. 7 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Mar. 11 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Oct. 11 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Oct. 29 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Nov. [N.D.] (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Dec. 2 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Dec. 7 (Box 13, Folder 30)
- Oversized (Newspaper Box)
  - 1830
    - Apr. 7 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - May 19 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Nov. 27 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Dec. 11 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Dec. 21 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1831
    - Jan. 8 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Feb. 11 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Feb. 24 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - July 8 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Sept. 9 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Sept. 26 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Nov. 9 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 1832
    - May 7 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - May 20 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Sept. 24 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - 1833
    - Feb. 14 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - June 21 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Sept. 6 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Nov. 29 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - 1834
    - Mar. 7 (Box 14, Folder 20)